{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following toxin causing botulism is less toxic to human beings?", "opta": "Type A", "optb": "Type B", "optc": "Type C", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a food infection?", "opta": "Salmonellois", "optb": "Botulism", "optc": "Staphylococcal intoxication", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The staphylococcal intoxication refers to presence of", "opta": "an enterotoxin", "optb": "neurotoxin", "optc": "mycotoxin", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bacterial food intoxication refers to", "opta": "illness caused by presence of pathogens", "optb": "food borne illness caused by the presence of a bacterial toxin formed in food", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The method of successful treatment of botulism prior to appearance of botulism symptoms involve administration of", "opta": "antibiotic", "optb": "analgesic", "optc": "antitoxin", "optd": "antipyretic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Botulism is caused by the presence of toxin developed by", "opta": "Clostridium tyrobutyricum", "optb": "Clostridium sporogenes", "optc": "Clostridium botulinum", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true to prevent botulism from smoked fish?", "opta": "The fish should be heated at its coolest part to at least 82\u00b0C for 30 min during or after smoking", "optb": "Fish should be immediately frozen after packaging and kept frozen", "optc": "Good sanitation should be maintained throughout production and handling", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Salmonellois is caused by the", "opta": "enterotoxin of Salmonella spp", "optb": "endotoxin of Salmonella spp", "optc": "neurotoxin of Salmonella spp", "optd": "exoenterotoxin of Salmonella spp", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Group I C. botulinum strains generally includes in", "opta": "all types of strains (proteolytic)A, B and F", "optb": "all types of strains (non-proteolytic) E and F", "optc": "all types of strains (proteolytic)C, D and F", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The application of Gamma rays destroys botulism toxin. The dose of gamma rays required for this purpose is", "opta": "73 Gy", "optb": "73 Rad", "optc": "7.3 Mrad", "optd": "173 Rad", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Arrange the potencies of toxin in descending order of the following canned foods", "opta": "peas>string beans>spinach> corn", "optb": "corn> string bean>peas>spinach", "optc": "corn> spinach> peas>string beans", "optd": "corn> peas>string beans>spinach", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The milk streptococci produce acetoin that gets spontaneously oxidized yielding a flavorings agent (responsible for aroma of butter) that is", "opta": "acetone", "optb": "acetyl coA", "optc": "butyric acid", "optd": "diacetyl", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The botulism intoxication occurs due to", "opta": "an enterotoxin", "optb": "neurotoxin", "optc": "mycotoxin", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Bacillus cereus causes gasteroenteritis by the production of an exoenterotoxin which is released in food as a result of", "opta": "cell growth", "optb": "cell autolysis", "optc": "cell permeation", "optd": "cell damage", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Staphylococcal intoxication is caused by the toxin m the food from", "opta": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optb": "S. cerevisiae", "optc": "S. thermophillus", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}